Hey everybody,
welcome
Everyone
All
right.
>> [clears throat]
>> Can you hear me now?
All right. Testing one, two. Testing
one, two.
Uh, you guys can hear me now.
Should be should be much better.
I was actually on the wrong mic just
now. So,
uh,
now I'm waiting for the ones.
Are we good?
All right, y'all. Okay, I was just about
to go uh go off camera again and see if
I could get this thing working. So, we
are good to go. Excellent. Excellent.
Excellent. Um, all right, guys. So, uh,
we're going to be, um, just going, uh,
going over some more of the photo
theology
Bible study suite tonight. By the way,
uh, how many of you
have been able to watch the story of the
T horns? You all put a five in the chat
if you were able to watch the story of
the T horns. That is the live that we
did uh Friday
Friday night. Friday night. And um
if you haven't gotten an opportunity
to go and watch that, please
make sure that you go back. It is on my
YouTube channel. Please make sure that
you go back and watch that. It is a It
is a mustsee. Not a shouldsee,
but a mustsee.
Okay. Um,
so guys, let's jump in. Let's jump in
and I'm going to go ahead and share my
screen.
Um,
all right. There we go. So once again
guys, this is the photo theology study
bible. Um, and
uh the website, let me just go ahead and
put it in the chat so you guys know how
to access it. Um,
it is uh the photoologybible.com.
Okay. photo theologybible.com.
All right. So, you should see it there
in
uh in the chat.
And uh what I want to do today is again
just go over a little bit of the
um the abilities of this
study Bible. Okay? And I'm going to say
this as well, guys. So, I don't know if
I shared this
uh I don't know if I shared this um the
last time that I was on
uh but maybe I shared it with my actual
photo theology class. So, you guys, I
typically use ESORD when I'm putting
together my sermons and doing my Bible
studies. And as I was creating this um
uh this software, I'm sorry, I put it in
the wrong uh place. Let me just
uh
Okay, there you go. So, as I was uh I've
been putting together this this
study tool
um for
probably the last two months. And when I
started
the goal was to put together a study
tool for my class, right? So, for um
those who are in my photo theology class
and other people that wanted to use this
app, but you know, for me, I was like,
I'm not going to use this. I'm sorry.
I'm not going to use this app just
because, you know, um
what I already
this is how I think. So, I'm just, you
know, I have no need to use this app.
And so, I would be working on the app,
trying to, you know, create the app for
my class. for those interested. But then
when I'm doing my own Bible study, I
just go back to Esword and I'm just
doing my thing, whatever. And then I was
like, you know what? If I'm making this
app, why would I not make it so that I
myself would like actually use this app
right while I am putting together um my
studies etc. And so I began to do that.
I was like, well, what what would I do
that would make me replace using E sword
with, you know, replace this for E
sword? And over the last again several
several weeks, this is what I began to
do. And I I'm letting you know guys that
this
um
this app is really really really
powerful. Um
uh it is I've designed it at this point
um as a tool
uh not only that other people could use
but that I use myself. Okay. And um it
is uh pretty robust.
Pretty robust. So let me uh I'm going to
walk you through. So, like I said, every
Sunday I'm going to get on and just do a
quick walkthrough of different things
the app can do. Um, and I'm going to
show you some things uh tonight. So, let
me go back to uh we're going to go to
the palace. So, once again, the palace
tab
and let me just scroll through here. All
right, these are all the different tabs
of all that this Bible software does. I
had mentioned this a little bit earlier
or or at least last week that this study
I was calling it an app at first, but an
app really gives an a in an insufficient
concept. It makes it
it is misleading.
You can use it on your phone, sure. But
I will tell you that
um just like with, you know, when I'm
using Esort or Logos or whatever Bible
software, I'm typically using it on my
computer. if you're serious about
getting into the word of God.
Um,
again, you can use it on your phone, but
I found the desktop to be just a lot
more uh user friendly for deep Bible
study. Okay,
so um again, these are all the different
tabs that are in this um this software
and I want to take you
I want to take you here uh back to the
palace for a little while. Okay. So,
here is the palace, the palace tab. And
what the palace tab is is it basically
describes
um
the concept of the entire palace, right?
You will find on this page that the
photoology palace has eight floors. So
here's the first floor, second, third,
all the way down to the eighth floor.
There are eight floors and each floor uh
has different rooms. And these different
rooms
um contain principles that we apply to
the Bible when we're studying any given
text, any given passage, etc. Um I did
go over this last week, but I just want
to run over it again quickly with you
guys. Okay. So, in the story room,
that's the first room on the first
floor. Uh the whole goal of this room is
basically to um to equip yourself or
equip your palace, furnish your palace
with as many stories of the Bible
um that you can store in that room. The
whole idea behind this is the more
stories you have stored in the story
room, the more you have to pull from
when it comes time to actually do Bible
study. So, uh, the story room in this
app is basically designed to teach you
how to just remember the basic tenants
of a story, right? So, for example, if I
click on story sequence uh, gallery,
right? It'll say, "Choose one chapter
from Genesis. Create five distinct
frames or major events within that
story. Add symbolic visual elements to
each frame. Practice recalling the story
through your images." Right? Pretty
simple, pretty straightforward. Um, and
as you scroll down, you're just going to
see like different exercises, right?
You'll see graphics,
um, you'll see examples. So, if I click
on this example tab, uh, here is Genesis
37. And here's how it breaks down the
story of Genesis 37. It's Joseph,
there's dream, there's a coat, pit,
caravan, Egypt, Piper, right? So, you're
remembering the basic elements of the
story just by okay, here are the here
are the the uh, you know, maybe four or
five points in the story that I want to
remember in sequence. so that I can have
this story basically locked in. If I go
to the to the um to the Bible story
library, you will see that it is
populated with different stories from
the Bible. Right? So, if I click on
Genesis and I scroll down, you'll just
see it's not going into the detail of
the story. It's just giving you like a
basic uh uh description of what's
happening in these various stories.
Right? So, the whole goal of the story
room as I teach my photo theology class
is [clears throat] not to necessarily
understand the stories right away and
their spiritual significance, but it's
just to get the stories in the palace.
Right? the more stories I have in the
palace, um, the the better my study will
be as I begin to go through the palace.
So, I'm going to go back and I want to
go now to the imagination room. And in
the imagination room, guys, this is kind
of like a quick tutorial which I'm going
to be doing. Uh, it is a quick tutorial
on the principles of of the palace,
right?
So
the imagination room is really designed
to teach you how to use your imagination
as you are studying the text. Right? So
if you're looking at the story of the
Exodus,
um you're training your mind to imagine
like walk through the story of Exodus as
if you were there, right? Think of it as
godly imagination. You're using your
imagination to help enhance the text,
right? Imagine being in the garden of
Gethsemane where Jesus is praying and
and in your imagination in in your
imagination,
see the anguish that Jesus is going
through in the garden as he prays.
There's something very powerful about
imagining using godly imagination when
you apply to the Bible. It it kind of
seasons a text, right? Seasons a story,
adds life to a story that you typically
wouldn't get just reading the text,
right, without applying like, man, what
must that have felt like as they're
walking through the Red Sea and, you
know, the droplets of water maybe just
splashing, you know, across their brow
or whatever. you're you're you're
thinking through what must it have been
like, right? You're giving it an added
dimension when you use the imagination
room. So again, nothing really uh
nothing like whoa, what is that? It's
just learning to use pictures.
Remember, the whole theme of photo
theology is that a picture is worth a
thousand words. If I'm training my mind
to learn to think in pictures, right,
I'm going to be able to memorize, I'm
going to be able to understand
uh a lot more of the scriptures because
I'm using
a method that works with the brain.
A picture is worth a thousand words. So
again, you go through the imagination
room and you'll just see they're telling
you different things like, you know, uh
uh using your imagination, you know, to
apply to this story of the Bible or that
story of the Bible, etc. Okay, so um not
too much detail there. These rooms on
the first floor are very simple. Okay,
very simple. Um the 24 frames per second
room. Now, many of you are probably
familiar with this concept from the
photo theology palace. I've been on
multiple times talking about this 24
frames per second. But the whole idea is
to take one chapter of the Bible at a
time and translate that chapter, the
theme of that chapter into one image.
And you want to do this for 24 chapters
at a time.
So, if I begin Genesis 1- 24,
um, and I'm going to take one verse or
one chapter, chapter 1, and say, "Okay,
what image can I use to summarize what
Genesis chapter 1 is all about?" I can
make that image
as vivid as I as I possibly can. And I
every time I see that image, I'm going
to remember, oh, Genesis 1 is about
creation. And this is what you're doing
24 chapters at a time. So you're
actually learning uh you're trying to
memorize Genesis 1- 24. So that you know
if I say Genesis chapter 17 to you,
you're going to be able to say, "Oh
yeah, that's where Abraham is
circumcised."
Or if I say Genesis chapter 19, you're
going to be you're going to be able to
say, "Oh yeah, that's where Sodom and
Gomorrah are destroyed." Right? You're
learning to think in pictures. So the
the 24 frames per second room does just
this, right? And as you can see here,
the 24 sets are already broken up,
right? If I click on these 24, you're
going to see that it's already populated
with images, right? It's already
populated with images. Now, I'm going to
show you something else. Uh, I'm going
to come back up to the top here and I
just want to go over to the PT
photoology image bible just for a
minute. And if I click on a photo
theology image bible,
um, it's now it's now not breaking these
uh these up into 24 frames per second or
24 chapters at a time. Uh, it's actually
just doing it by book. So I can scroll
down and say I want to study the book. I
want to memorize the book of Esther, the
chapters of Esther. And if I click on
study this book, um you'll see it pop up
and you can actually test yourself using
these images, right? Um and it'll tell
you, hey, this chapter is about this
thing right here. It's going to tell you
what the image is. If I click flip the
card, it's going to tell you, okay,
here's what's happening in this image,
and here's why the here's why you're
using this image, right? to connect with
this particular chapter.
So this is for the entire Bible,
right? So it is the tab is called the PT
image Bible, the photo theology image
bible. And as I scroll down, scroll
down, scroll down, this is going all the
way to the book of revelation. meaning
you can you can you can strive to
memorize the themes of every chapter of
the Bible just by memorizing the images.
You're not memorizing words, you're
memorizing themes. Okay, so
that's the 24 frames per second room and
the uh what we just talked about the the
photo theology um image bible. Okay. So,
just if y'all are following, put a one
in the chat. I want to make sure that
y'all, if you have any questions, by the
way, ask it in the chat. Okay. Ask it in
the chat. Um, let me come back to the
palace tab and I'm going to go down to
the Bible rendered room. And in the
Bible rendered room, it's the same
principle, but this time I'm using I'm
taking all 24 chapters. So remember,
we're doing 24 chapters at a time. This
time you're taking the 24 chapters,
Genesis 1- 24, and now you're saying,
what is the major theme
of these 24 chapters?
I want to juice that theme down into one
image. And as I look at Genesis 1 and I
scan Genesis 1- 24 and I look at the
theme of these 24 chapters, you will
find that the theme is division. You
have Adam and Eve
separating from God. You have Cain and
Abel. You have uh the serpent and the
seed. You have uh Abraham or you have uh
um the tower of Babel. You have uh Noah
in the flood. You have um uh uh Abraham
and Lot. You have Abraham coming out of
of um of right? You've got all this
separation happening. Um, I said Abraham
and Lot, uh, Isaac and Ishmamail.
The theme is division.
So, what you do is you take those 24
chapters and now you say, I'm just going
to use one symbol, the division sign, to
remind me that these first 24 chapters
of the book of the Bible, the theme is
division. If you go from Genesis 25 to
the end of the book of Genesis, you will
find that everything there is about
multiplication. So that by the end of
the book, you have Israel as a great
multitude
in Egypt. So now I'm going to use the
multiplication sign to to summarize the
last half of the book of Genesis. And
suddenly now between the division sign
and the multiplication sign, I have now
basically
skimmed the entire book of Genesis in in
under a second just by you memorizing
the themes and going, "Yeah, division,
multiplication,
and then you're doing this for the
entire Bible." Meaning if you can
memorize these 50 images, 51 images that
are covering 24 chapters at a time with
the exception of Genesis 25-50, but are
covering 24 chapters at a time. You can
actually scan the entire Bible
just by
um just by memorizing the 20 the the 50
images. You can run through the entire
story of the Bible in under a minute. If
you get the images down where you're
like, "Yep, that image means that. That
image represents this. That image
represents this time period, etc." You
can actually scan the entire Bible in
like 30 seconds or less in your mind.
You guys, that is absolutely crazy. And
we've done it in class over and over and
over and people are stunned like how do
we just do that? Okay,
so that is the palace room. Um,
and now I'm going to hit go back to the
tab. Uh, I'm sorry. Did I say that's a
palace room? That is the Bible rendered
room. Let me go to two other rooms very
quickly and then I'm going to show you
one more thing and then we're going to
wrap this up. Okay. So, back on the
palace tab, first floor again. Um, I
want to go to the translation room and
let me talk to you a little bit about
the translation room. So, in the
translation room, right, you are not
translating verses. You're not
translating like Hebrew to Greek or
Greek. You're not translating language.
You're translating words into images.
So the idea behind this this room is
basically learning how to take a text
and then if you had to explain that text
just using
pictures, an image, a storyline, how
would you explain that text? And so um
that is what this room is designed to
do, right? You're you're practicing
to translate verses into images. Why?
Because a picture is worth a thousand
words. So I'm going give you an example.
If I put in here Romans chapter 8 verse1
translate to word picture
and here is the word therefore. There is
therefore now no condemnation to those
who are in Christ Jesus. And here is the
image that um
that is produced. Now remember this is
designed to help you, right? You don't
have to use this image, but it's
designed to give you an example. Here's
the example. A courtroom appears. A
judge sits on a high bench. An accused
person stands before the judge. A heavy
book of law of laws lie open. A long
scroll displays all the accused wrong
deeds. The accused head hangs low.
Condemnation is a heavy shadow. Then a
figure steps forward. That figure is
Christ Jesus. He stands directly in
front of the accused. His he envelopes
the accused in his presence.
The shadow of condemnation dissipates.
The judge looks down from the bench. The
judge sees only Christ Jesus. The scroll
of the wrong deeds vanish. A clean bank
blank paper is seen. No charges remain
written. The accused is now hidden with
Christ. No condemnation
can reach them there.
Okay.
So, um,
so,
uh, who is that? Mimi Moore 11. I just
see I see what you just said. If you,
um, if you will send me an email, I'm
going to make sure that, uh, you're not
getting that error message that you need
to uh, that you need to uh to update
your trial. Okay? So, contact me through
the app or in fact, I have your email
address.
Yeah, if you contact me through the app
so I can get your email address, I will
get that cleared up so you can uh you'll
no longer see that sign as you sign in
and log into the to the software. Okay.
All right. Um
so,
uh that's right. The the 24 uh the
Genesis Highrise, it's built off of the
24 frames per second room. Okay. So, let
me go back to the let me go back to the
um to the translation room. This is what
the translation room does. Um the
address for the software you guys is
once again it is photoologybible.com.
If you look up in the chat you will see
it there. Just scroll up and you will
see the site photoologybible.com.
So again, any verse that I put into
this, say, "Hey, I want to translate
this." It'll translate it for me. And
again, I can choose to use that as a I
like that image. Or I can say, you know
what? I want to come up with my own um
my own picture, right? My own
translation for this particular verse.
All right. So that is the translation
room. I'm going to share with you one
more room and then I'm going to share
with you an exercise and I'm going to
need your your help with this, okay? Cuz
we're going to do a quick Bible study.
Y'all down for a Bible study? This is
going to be real quick. Not an in-depth
study, but it will be an in-depth study
at the same time. You'll see what I
mean. Um, so back on the first floor
here is the gems room. So, what is a
gem? Um,
a gem is that special aha moment where
you're like, "Oh
man, I uh I never saw this verse like
this before. I never saw this story like
this before. Oh man, I never saw that
connection between this verse and this
verse before." It's that aha moment when
[clears throat] I was um just becoming
uh an Adventist. I remember, you know,
having still in still being in the
hip-hop industry
and being rappers, we would have our
little notepads and every time a lyric,
right, a thought came to mind, we would
take out and start writing down our
lyrics. But when I started becoming
Christian, I was doing the same thing.
Instead of writing down lyrics only, now
I was writing down, oh man, I Whoa,
Genesis 3:15. Oh man, I never saw
Genesis 3:15. The I whoa, the Lord just
gave me something powerful and I would
write it down. It was a gem. Okay, so
the gem room is basically that room
where we collect all of those aha
moments. You're gonna get some of those
aha moments while using this Bible
software. You might get them while
you're out at work, wherever. But the
whole idea of the gems room is
collecting these gems so that you don't
forget them. When you're using the app
and a thought hits you or you know,
you're doing a a study on the my study
tab and something pops up where you're
like, "Oh man, this is deep." You can
actually say, "Save this as a gem." and
it'll automatically save it to the gems
library. Okay, the gems library.
And so you can see here there are, you
know, a few like sample gems that are
already in the gems library. But as
you're using the software and you're
you're learning things and and you know
uh uh coming into greater understanding,
you can always say, man, this is a gem.
I want to save this as a gem. And it'll
automatically save. Okay. Now,
now I'm going to take you over to
the study buddy tab right here. The
study buddy tab. And what is the study
buddy tab? So, the study buddy tab.
Imagine imagine having a
um that friend that you're you're doing
a study and you're like, "Yo, have you
ever thought of this this this and
this?"
And
uh
yeah just a messenger it is my
experience right that uh using this on
the desktop on a laptop is a lot more
user friendly than it is on the phone.
You can use it on the phone. I've used
it on the phone. But people who who
think, "Oh, it's just a phone app." And
they're using on the phone and they're
like, "Okay, what?" When they see it for
the first time on a desktop, they're
like, "Oh, wow.
I I didn't know that all this was here."
Okay. So,
I'm I'm I'm plugging the desktop
version, but I'm not against the phone
version. Okay? I I have them both, but I
know like for me, like I said, when I'm
if you are trying to like really utilize
this, uh it's going to be a lot more
efficient on a desktop. Okay. So, what
is the study buddy tab? The study buddy
is, like I was saying, imagine that that
friend that you know you can call up.
You're like, "Man, I'm going through
this study and I was thinking this
thought." And then your friend is like,
"Oh, wait a minute. Have you thought
about this? Have you thought about maybe
connecting this with that?" And then
you're like, "Wait, what?" And you know,
you're going back and forth. That is
that is the purpose of the study buddy.
Okay. So, I'm going to I actually was
just before we got on, I got on I said,
"Hey, listen. I I we just need to start
over. Let me let me go ahead and just
start from scratch. And I'm going to ask
you guys, okay? Hey guys, what would you
like to study? Give me something, a
verse, a uh a story, a parable, just
just whatever.
Just whatever. Again, um the
address for the app is the Bible is uh
photoologybible.com.
It is in the chat. I will put it in the
in the uh link underneath the video once
this is uploaded, but it is
photoologybible.com.
Okay. So, what do y'all want to study?
And we're not about to do a whole study,
you guys, but I'm just showing you an
example.
You're you're you know saying to
yourself today, hey, you know what? I
want to study what? Put it in the chat.
Give me the verse. Give me the parable.
Give me the thought. May not even be a
verse or a p. It's just a thought. Man,
I want to study, you know, um, how does
righteousness relate to the sanctuary.
So, I'm waiting for for y'all to to put
something in the chat.
Or I might just go with that. I might
just go with that. So let let me let me
do this. I'm going to say um okay um
all right. So I'm going to study
the connection
between
the sanctuary
and
All right.
Yeah, my computer's
freezing up.
I got to give it a second here. Yeah, my
my computer's uh giving me a little bit
of uh some issues over the last several
weeks. So,
let me let it get its time to unfreeze
itself. And if not, then I might just
refresh the page. So, hold on.
All right, y'all. Well, my computer is
definitely just frozen up uh for no
reason, but now's a good time to see
what y'all are putting in the chat. John
17:17,
the unjust steward, the fruits of the
spirit. Um,
wow, my page isn't even reloading.
All right, give me one second.
Okay, let's Okay.
Okay.
So, let me go back to study buddy. All
right. So, let's do
uh
Let's do I want to study
John 17:17
in connection
with the
sanctuary.
Oh, John 17:17.
So I want you to see when I put John
17:17 that it just populated the text
immediately. Um so let's say I want to
study
John uh 17:17.
Um
uh in the context
oh it's it's bringing up Jonah 17.
That's why. Okay, let me rephrase that.
Sorry. So John
17:17,
let's study
this in the context of the sanctuary.
Okay. Now I want you to notice
what's going on here. So I just put
let's study this
in the context of the sanctuary. And I
want you to notice what's happening as
I'm typing. So I want you to look over
here.
Uh where Jes
is actually looking at what you're
writing. It says this brilliant. You've
stumbled onto something wonderful.
Moving from All right. Kind of thought I
was talking about Jonah's story, but
we're not. We're talking about John
17:17 is a mass.
Okay. So, it just connected Jonah and
John 17,
which I did not intend for it to do, but
let's go with it. So, uh it's as if
you're following the path of the priest
moving from the depths of death and
sacrifice Jonah and the altar into the
refined atmosphere of the sanctuary
proper. So, I just want you to see,
[laughter]
man, I do y'all see what just happened?
So, what is just done
accidentally? Because I thought I was
saying I want to study Jonas uh Jonah
in the belly of the the belly of the
whale with John 17:17
in the context of the sanctuary.
And it's just given me a seed thought
that
uh
Jonah's experience
is in essence a parallel of Christ's
experience at the altar of sacrifice
which I've just I mean of course you you
think about Jonah that's death but like
to actually connect the story of Jonah
with
the sacrifice of Christ at the altar of
sacrifice in the context of the
sanctuary.
I'm already like, okay, I have a seed
that I can now I can now say, all right,
good. Thank you. I already know what my
next sermon is going to be. Jonah and
the altar of sacrifice.
And and I may just go and say, "Okay,
I'm going to take the the the altar of
sacrifice. I'm going to take the story
of Jonah and I'm going to look at all
the ways that that or all the parallels
I can find
between the altar of sacrifice
and Jonah's story.
Okay. Now, uh Lisa, I see your your your
uh question. By the way, I I let me
share this. No, I'll come back to that
in a moment. I'm for you for all of you
who are on Patreon. I'm gonna um speak
to you in a moment about getting access
to the to the software. Okay. So,
I'm gonna continue on what it says.
Right. When Jesus says set them apart
in truth, he's using sanctuary language.
In the Old Testament, things weren't
just good, they were holy because they
were physically set apart for God's use.
By calling the word truth, he's making
the Bible our environment, our
tabernacle.
Then it says, "I'm curious what drew you
to connect these two specifically."
Well, you guys, I didn't connect these
two specifically, but you see what's
happening, right?
Accidentally.
Accidentally,
we now have a study on Jesus saying,
"Set them apart by thy word." And
remember, the sanctuary is designed to
set apart, to sanctify
a people unto God.
And so now you have this connection of
wait a minute. So in order for me to be
set aside,
I too have to experience
that Jonah story. Not necessarily
running away from God, but having that
death, burial, resurrection experience
that sets me aside
to be able to experience the sanctuary.
Now guys, we're just freestyling, right?
I listen, the purpose of this the
purpose of this note section, right, is
for you to actually keep writing. I've
only written one sentence.
One sentence, y'all.
And I'm going to show you what's coming
next. What is the idea of being Now, by
the way,
if you do this 20 times, it's going to
give you to it's never going to give you
the same thing. It's dynamic. What is it
doing? It's actually pulling from the
photo theology principles and applying
it to the text in real time.
Okay. So, it goes on to say, uh, what is
the idea of being hidden in the fish and
hidden in truth? It's a marvelous
thought to chew on. Shall we see if we
can find the furniture of the tabernacle
hidden in these verses in John 17? So,
it's giving you different ideas, right?
different uh uh uh concepts that you can
say, hey, I want to follow that line of
reasoning. I want to follow that
thought. Let me go down to this sparks
section. So, what is a spark?
You will see as you're in any section of
the Bible, right? You will see that any
section of the of the software that you
may be typing something out and you'll
see something pop up that looks like
this and it's called a spark. what's
happening when you're when you're
writing a thought out, when you're
writing a study out. And remember, this
software is not designed to write your
study for you. It is designed to help
you think outside the box. That's what
it's doing right now. So, when a spark
comes up, it's basically
the the the software saying, "Wait a
minute, have you thought about
connecting what you just said with this
or that, etc.?" If you're putting
together your sermon in this software
and as you're writing out some powerful
thought, you're going to see sparks
coming up in the top right hand corner.
If you hit on that spark, it's going to
say what you just said about this, this,
this, and this is a powerful idea. Or it
might not be a powerful idea, but it's
going to say, have you thought about
connecting that with this? Have you
thought about applying this principle
from the palace to this?
And basically you guys what ends up
happening is whereas one study
might have you just on a you know on a
single track of okay that was a good
study and I'm done. Now from one study
you are having multiple seeds planted
that you could follow days later weeks
later months later years later. Let me
keep reading. So uh the set them apart
sanctification in John 17 in John 17
parallels the swallowing of Jonah both
involving both hidden away from the
world in a specific vessel one in the
fish the other in truth to be prepared
for for a mission. You know that is so
interesting. I've never thought about
um Jonah being hidden in the belly of
the fish.
It's almost as if when we die, we are
that concept of being hidden in Christ
only comes about as we die
in Christ.
Right? When we are dead in Christ, we
are hidden in him. It's a thought I've
never had before. Um, but using the
photo theology principles of saying,
have you considered this?
Have you considered that
I when Paul says I'm crucified with
Christ, nevertheless I live, yet not I,
but Christ that lives in me.
That when we are dead and hidden in him,
which you guys is what happens when we
enter the sanctuary.
When we enter the sanctuary, we are
hidden as it were from the world. We are
hidden as it were
from the old ways. The sanctuary
is the thing that separates us from the
world. Is the thing that invites us to
die to self. Is the thing that is in
essence supposed to swallow us up.
Yeah. Yeah. Let me keep going.
Um,
in the sanctuary, the word is the most
lit. It is most literally found inside
the ark of the covenant. The 10 words to
be set apart in the word is to be placed
within the holy of holies. You guys,
these are all these are all just
different. Like, hey, if you're studying
these two, consider this connection.
Consider this connection. Consider this
connection. Now
the software just said the word of God
was most literally found in the ark in
the most holy place. Thus to be set
aside by the word
is in essence to be set aside within
that mo within that ark. It is the ark
of the covenant wherein the word of God
is found
that God desires ultimately to set us
aside and sanctify us and make us most
holy.
He that dwelleth in a secret place of
the most high shall abide under the
shadow of the almighty. Now listen you
guys. Um
once again what I want you to see is we
were initially just going to study set
them apart. You know set them aside by
thy word by thy word. Thy word is truth.
John 17:17
and accidentally connected that with the
story of Jonah.
And now we're beginning to see this
thought whoa like Jonah
which is a a symbol of Christ's death
which is ultim ultimately supposed to be
a symbol of our death. When we are dead
in Christ, we are hidden with him.
We are hidden in him.
We experience that death, burial, and
resurrection. So that when we come out,
when Jonah was was, you know, made it
out of that three-day experience, he was
a different person.
Still not a perfect person, but he was a
different person.
He was a man now intent on fulfilling
the mission of God.
Can it be that that spit that dying to
self is meant to swallow up the old man?
Whoa.
Whoa, y'all. Can it be that in that
Jonah experience, the old man dies and a
new man comes in his place? Is this not
what the altar of sacrifice is designed
to do? Is this not what the sanctuary is
designed to do?
We go in one way and come out another.
The old man dies
and a new man comes out. So again, you
guys, now listen
this. I'm just going to scroll.
We're not going to read all this. I'm
just going to scroll. This is all that's
come up from one sentence.
But remember when I've come to this to
this study, I didn't come with just one
sentence in mind, right? I'm kind of
freestyling right now. What I'm saying
is I already let's say I've already got
like I know what I want to study and I
got a bunch of thoughts going through my
mind. So let's say all right, I said I
want to let's study John 17:17. Let's
study this in the context of the
sanctuary. I think I think that each
article
of furniture
um is
uh designed to set us apart
in some way from the world. Okay. So now
I've just enter you see I'm typing
and
uh yes uh yes Franco the analyze my
thought does something similar but it's
a lot more it's it's a little bit
different and I'll talk about that when
we get to the analyze my thought app.
This is more of an interactive the
analyze my thought. It just gives you
gives you everything at one time and
says here's the strength of your thought
da da da da da. This is more
interactive. Jeez is actually talking
with you as you are doing this study. So
what I just put I think that each
article of furniture is designed to set
us apart in some way from the world. Um
let's see what happens here.
Okay.
All right. So, oh, what a marvelous uh
intuition you've had. John 17. No, no,
no. This is still John 17. Um,
okay.
So, now we got a new spark. The word as
the golden lampstand. Uh, the word as
the golden lampstand. In the holy place,
the only light comes from the oil fuel
lamps. If Jesus is the word and the
light, John 1:1, then being set apart in
truth is walking in the specific glow of
the sanctuary rather than the natural
sun of the outer court. In other words,
the light of the candlestick it the
Jesus now giving you a a concept, an
idea. Okay, wait a minute. soul,
the light of the candlestick in the holy
place. There is something about that
light
and Jesus being the light of the world
that is designed to set us apart and
it's a spark. If I click explore this
now,
it will actually give me a little bit
more information. Okay. So now, as you
can see, it's just refreshed.
The sanctification process follows the
priestly path. The washing, labor,
eating bread, and shine and uh and
shining.
The sanctification process follows the
priestly path. Washing the labor, eating
bread, and shining the lampstand. We're
called to shine. Again, what you're
seeing here is that every time you put
in a verse, a text,
um,
you will see sparks come up. Every time
you put in a thought, you're going to
see a spark come up that says, "Okay,
let's track this thought. let me give
you something else that maybe you
haven't thought about or let me amplify
what you're saying by sharing this e
etc. And the power of this section you
guys is that listen this is this is so
far let me just remove this here. This
is so far
two sentences
from my study.
Two sentences
from the study. Every time I write a new
sentence, Jeeves,
not Jesus.
Jeez,
is recalculating
according to what I'm saying, what I'm
writing, and then it's going to, hey,
have you thought about this? What about
this connection? What about that
connection? So, as you can see, you
guys, if you end up writing out, you
know, man, I had these thoughts and
you're you're writing these thoughts out
and you're writing five, six, seven, 10,
10 sentences, I want you to imagine,
just imagine,
y'all get the picture.
Just imagine
how much you can pull
from using this particular page, the
study buddy,
to help amplify
your your thoughts as you're studying,
to help make connections that you may
have never thought about making before.
Jonah
and Jesus and the altar of sacrifice,
which opens up a whole study on being
set apart and what the sanctuary, which
is designed to sanctify us, meaning set
us apart. And now you got a whole study.
Now you got a whole series.
Now you're taking each article of
furniture in the sanctuary and you're
showing
how
being set apart
must be done through a process that must
begin with a Jonah experience of dying,
death, burial, and resurrection, which
by the way is exactly what the altar of
sacrifice and the labor, which are both
in the outer court, demonstrate. death
at the altar of sacrifice, burial at the
labor, and washing and resurrection at
the labor. Both of those articles of
furniture is the beginning experience of
being sanctified and set aside.
All right. So guys, um that's it.
That's our lesson for today on the photo
the photo theology Bible study suite.
You can try it out for yourself. I
haven't even finished everything that
you can do on this page, but uh this is
a this is a general overview of just
this page, you guys. Just the study
buddy. Just the study buddy.
I'm going to go ahead and show you this
last thing here.
So if you want to simmer this,
[clears throat]
let's say, hey, I want to take this idea
um let's study the sanctuary and this
connection
um that sets us apart. I also
want to connect
um
Jonah's experience with the bornag again
experience.
Okay. And what I want to do, it's going
to make comments. It's going to add
comments about the born again experience
uh in the in the uh in the sparks. So,
you see it refreshing here. Uh Jonah's
descent into the roots of the mountains
reflects the deep the depth, the abyss,
marrying the sanctuary's labor. Uh, and
it's going to go on and just bring up
more thoughts. But I want to take this.
I'm gonna copy and I'm going to go over
to simmer
and um I'm going to go ahead and uh
let's see here.
I'm going to put in the theme Jonah
uh Jonah's
experience
parallels
the bornag again
experience
and
I'm going to hit start simmer and what
this start simmer is going to do is it
is going to
it is going to run this thought
through all
rooms of the photo theology palace. It's
going to use a different principle in
each room, but it's going to produce a
simmer. So, it's going to just sit there
and simmer, and when it's done, it's
going to
basically show you 37 different avenues,
37 different ways, 37 different routes
you can take
studying this one thought.
All right, I'm going to end it right
here, you guys. Um, I'm going to put
um my email in
in the link. Okay,
email me at um a burninghammergmail.com.
For those of you that are on Patreon,
by the way, if you're on Patreon, and I
mentioned this before, if you are on
Patreon or Teachable and you are
currently
uh on a subscription for the photo
theology class, you automatically have
free access to
this software.
Okay.
So,
um if
if you are already on Patreon or if you
are already um in any of my classes,
Teachable, etc. Um you already have
access. You may not have this yet, but
you have access. You don't have you have
free access. It's not free, but you have
access to this already because you're
already subscribed. For those of you
that are not subscribed, you can either
subscribe to the app or you can
subscribe, become a subscriber to
Patreon and if you enter into one of my
classes, you will automatically get
access to the app. Okay, so
I'm going to put my Patreon link
um in
the link under the video. I will also
put the link to the Bible study uh page.
So, you will see both of those. Um for
those of you that that are in Teachable,
the same thing. And if any of you that
are already in Patreon are having
difficulty
um getting access to the app for
whatever reason, email me a burning
hammer just as you spell it, a burning
hammergmail.com.
All right. All right, guys. That's it.
Thank you. Um, this uh is again
uh like I said, I'm using this now for
my own personal study and I cannot tell
you uh how like just
absolutely amazing this thing is. Okay,
so check it out. You will not be
disappointed. And again, guys, um I'm
going to go ahead and wrap this up. Have
a good evening and uh may God bless you
and I will see you next Sunday as we
will go into more detail and we're going
to do some deeper Bible studies. We're
going to start actually doing Bible
studies with your help kind of like what
we were doing with Freestyle Wednesdays,
but we're going to be going through a
more detailed process as I walk you
through more um capabilities of this
Bible software. All right.
Okay. Um,
yeah, Jonathan, look out for something
from me, okay? I do have your number, so
look out for something from from me,
okay? All right. Blessings, everyone.
Have a good rest of your evening.